Then, we talk about distributed computing.
当我们讨论分布式计算时
We generally refer to a big computational job,
我们通常说的是超大的计算任务
executive across a cluster of nodes.
通常要通过节点集群来计算
Each node is responsible for a set of operations on a subset of the data.
每个节点都要处理部分的数据
At the end, we combine these partial results to get the final answer.
最后我们把这些处理后的结果合并得到最后结果
But how do the nodes know which task to run and demote order?
但是这些节点是如何知道以什么顺序去跑哪些任务呢？
Are all nodes equal?
所有的节点都一样吗？
Which machine are you interacting with when you run your code?
当你跑代码时 你用的是哪台机器？
Most computational frameworks are organized into master worker hierarchy.
计算框架以 Master-Worker 模式为主
Where the master node is responsible for orchestrating the tasks across the cluster,
其中主节点负责分配任务
while the workers are performing the actual computations.
工作节点负责执行计算
There are four different modes to setup Spark.
Spark有四种设置模式
The first one, is local mode.
第一种模式是单机模式
In this case, everything happens on a single machine.
在这种模式下 所有的计算都发生在一台电脑中
So, while we use spark's APIs,
虽然我们在使用 Spark的 API
we don't really do any distributed computing.
但我们并没有做任何的分布式计算
Local mode can be useful to learn syntax and to prototype your project.
单机模式对于学习语法和搭建项目雏形很有帮助
In lesson two, you will be performing operations in local mode
在第二节课里你会在单机模式下进行操作
in the classroom work spaces to become comfortable with the Spark syntax.
通过教室的工作空间 (Workspace)去学习 Spark 的语法
The other three modes are distributed and declare a cluster manager.
另外三种模式都是需要集群管理器的分布式模式
The cluster manager is a separate process that monitors the available resources,
集群管理器单独用来管理资源的
and makes sure that all machines are responsive during the job.
同时确保所有的机器运行任务时能及时响应
There are three different options of cluster managers,
集群管理器有三种选项
Sparks on Standalone Customer Manager,
Spark 自带的 独立集群管理器
YARN from the Hadoop project,
来自 Hadoop项目 的 YARN
and then other open source manager from UC Berkeley's AMPLab Coordinators.
和来自 UC Berkeley 的 AMPLab 的开源管理器
YARN are necessary useful when you are sharing a cluster with a team,
YARN 在需要和别人分享集群时 会非常有帮助
so you won't need them in this course.
目前 我们不涉及这种情况
Instead, you will set up and use
在第三节课里
your own distributed Spark cluster using Standalone mode in lesson three.
你会用 Standalone 模式搭建自己分布式 Spark 集群
In Spark's Standalone, we also have a so-called Driver Process.
在 Spark 的 Standalone 中 我们还有一个所谓的驱动程序
If you open a Spark shell,
如果你打开一个 Spark shell
either Python or Scala,
随便是 Python 或者 Scala,
you are directly interacting with the driver program.
你会和这个驱动程序直接进行交互
It acts as the master and is responsible for scheduling tasks,
它扮演着 Marster 的角色
that the executors we are performed.
负责给执行者分配任务